hematologylibrary.org 2014-04-03

# ASH Web Site Privacy Policy

## Last Updated: May 14, 2008

### 

The American Society of Hematology is committed to safeguarding the privacy of our Web site users. This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for _hematology.org_ and its affiliated sites (the "Site"), which is provided to you by the American Society of Hematology ("we" or "us" or "ASH"). This Privacy Policy governs our collection of information from you through your use of the Site. 

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. By viewing, browsing, accessing, or otherwise using this Site, you agree that such access and/or use, and any dispute regarding our online privacy practices, is governed by this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service. 

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy in the future as we deem necessary. If we do modify this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Privacy Policy on this Site and change the "Last Updated" date above to reflect the date of the changes. By continuing to use the Site after we post any such changes, you accept the Privacy Policy as modified.

## Children's Privacy

This children's privacy statement explains our Site's practices with respect to the online collection and use of personal information from children under the age of thirteen, and provides important information on your rights under federal law with respect to such information. 

This is a general audience Web site and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personally-identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, we will delete such information from our records. 

## Information Collection and Use

### Information Voluntarily Supplied to ASH by Our Members

We maintain data (including contact information, subspecialty, and ASH committee participation) on all of our members that can be accessed through a secure [online member directory](https://store.hematology.org/Default.aspx?tabid=64&redirecttabid=137). This directory may be accessed only by other current ASH members through a password-protected, members-only area of the Site. This directory is not made available to the general public. Members who wish to opt out of being included in the directory may do so by accessing their ****[member profile](https://store.hematology.org/Default.aspx?tabid=64&redirecttabid=137) online. 

We also offer a voluntary, publicly accessible online directory of members through [Find a Hematologist](http://www.findahematologist.org/). The Find a Hematologist directory allows patients and other members of the public to search for hematologists and provides users with contact information for members who have chosen to be listed. Participation in the directory is optional. ASH members must opt in to be included and may opt out at any time by accessing their [member profile](https://store.hematology.org/Default.aspx?tabid=64&redirecttabid=137)  ****online.

We do not share member e-mail addresses, phone numbers, or fax numbers with non-members or other organizations, except that we may share member information with third-party service providers, contractors, partners, and fulfillment agencies to use only for purposes of providing a service relating to the Site. 

We do, however, make our membership mailing list available to outside groups for educational purposes, including mailings about grant opportunities that could be beneficial to members, educational publications (e.g., medical textbooks, scientific journals), and educational programs or courses. ASH members who do not wish to have their mailing addresses shared with outside parties in this manner may opt out by contacting ASH Member Services at 202-776-0544 or _[membership@hematology.org](mailto:membership@hematology.org)_. 

Your member data also may be governed by the terms and conditions of your membership. In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Policy and any term(s) of your membership, the terms of your membership will govern.

### Information Voluntarily Supplied by Web Site Users  

Both ASH members and non-member users of this Site may be asked to enter personally identifiable information (such as name, phone number, mailing address, e-mail address) in order to perform certain functions on the Site, including ordering products, registering for meetings, submitting abstracts, and requesting additional information. By using the Site, you agree that we may provide any or all of such information to third parties, such as service providers, contractors, partners, and fulfillment agencies, in order to complete your transaction (e.g., to confirm an order, send materials, resolve billing issues).

You also agree that we may use any information submitted by or collected from you via the Site for any other purpose, including to contact you for customer service purposes, to inform you of important changes or additions to our Site or the services offered through our Site, and to send you administrative notices, offers, promotional correspondence, and any other communications that we believe may be of interest to you. 

### Information That Is Automatically Collected

We also may collect and store information that is generated automatically through a Web site analytics program as you navigate through our Site. For example, to help make the Site more responsive to the needs of users, we may employ, on our Site, or on certain pages of our Site, a standard feature of browser software, called a "cookie," to assign each user a unique, random number that resides on a user's computer. The cookie doesn't actually identify you, it just identifies the computer that you use to access the Site. The only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply (e.g., if you submit a username and password and ask that the Site remember that information the next time you visit). A cookie cannot read unrelated data off your hard drive. We use cookies to help us tailor the Site to your needs, to deliver a better, more useful service. For example, we may use cookies to track the pages on the Site visited by users, the number of site visitors, and search queries. We can make the Site more effective if we know which areas our users are visiting, how often, and the information that is most important to our users. Of course, you are free to set your Web browser not to accept cookies or delete the cookies that have been placed; however, doing so may render your computer unable to take advantage of the personalized features enjoyed by other users of the Site. 

## Other Uses

In addition to the uses described above, we may occasionally release information about visitors when release is appropriate to comply with law, to enforce our Terms of Service, or to protect the rights, property or safety of visitors to our Site, the public, or to us or our Site. 

## Credit Card Information

Users may be prompted to enter their credit card information, including, for example, when making purchases, renewing membership, or making a gift online. Any credit card information you may provide to us is secured during transmission over the Internet using industry-standard secure socket layer (SSL) encryption. We use your credit card information only to bill you for the products and services you order from us. We do not share your credit card information with anyone, except as may be necessary to process your transactions or comply with law. Users may click on the Verisign logo included on each payment page to view our Verisign certificate and to access information about the security status of our site. 

## Third-Party Sites

Our Site includes links to third-party Web sites whose privacy policies we do not control. Once you leave our Site, any information you provide at another site will be governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting, which may differ from ours. If you can't find the privacy policy of a third-party site via a link on the site homepage, you should contact the third-party provider directly for more information. 

## Storage of Information 

Information we gather on our Site is stored within controlled databases (hosted by us or by a third party on our behalf). As effective as the reasonable security measures implemented by us and our service providers may be, no security system is impenetrable. We cannot guarantee the security of any of our or our service providers' systems or databases nor can we guarantee that information supplied will not be intercepted while being transmitted over the Internet. 

## Questions?

Questions regarding privacy issues should be directed to the [ASH Webmaster](mailto:webmaster@hematology.org).

back to top
